

Alisson Fogaça Software QA Engineer

+34 647 04 82 60

Skype: live:alisson fogassa

□ alisson_fogassa@hotmail.com

Madrid, Spain

🛗 32 years old

My name is Alisson Fogaça and I live in Madrid, Spain. My backgrounds are Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Graduate Degree Technologies for Web Applications and Degree in Computer Education. I'm work with software tests about 13 years, having experiences as: Software quality assurance for REST API backend and for frontend web/desktop applications in betting, gambling, accounting, financial and real state area; Functional, nonfunctional, technical, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security and performance tests; Tests automation development for REST API with Java, Spring, REST Assured, Supertest and Cucumber; Tests automation development for web applications with JavaScript, Cypress and Cucumber; Utilization agile methodology as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms as Jira, Zephyr, Jenkins, Elastic, Couchbase, Kafka, AWS and Git; Web application development with language PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML and MySQL database; Performance as lead and computer teacher. I have a confident and commitment professional profile, besides, experiences in working with goals and deadlines. I try don't accommodate myself, I'm always improving and learning through of the new challenges and studies.



Experience

Software QA Engineer

Kindred

February 2023 – present

Responsible for software quality assurance for several backend API and frontend web applications in betting and gambling area. Test automation development for web applications and API with JavaScript, Cypress, Cucumber and Supertest. Functional, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security and mobile tests with iOS and Android. Tests on SQL and noSQL database. Utilization agile methodology as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms/technologies as Jira, Zephyr, BrowserStack, Elastic, Couchbase, Kafka and Git. In charge to training creation and presentation for users, traders and customers.

QA Lead

Matera

January 2021 – February 2023

Responsible for software quality assurance for REST API backend and for frontend web applications in accounting and financial area. Leading a QA team directly. Test automation development for REST API with Java, Spring, REST Assured and Cucumber. Functional, acceptance, reliability, system, integration, usability, regression, security, and performance tests with jMeter and Postman. Tests on MySQL e H2 database. Utilization agile methodology as Scrum and Kanban, and platforms as Jira, Zephyr, Jenkins, AWS, and Git. Tools and scripts development in PHP for support to software tests. Documents elaboration for customers.

Software QA Engineer

Thomson Reuters

July 2012 – January 2021

Responsible for software quality assurance for several applications in accounting and real estate area. Assigned to creation, preparation and execution of scripts and tests cases, besides utilization and application of the database language SQL. In charge to white and black box tests, and the utilization of Sybase SQL Anywhere 9 e 16 database. Responsible to trainings creation and presentation for users and customers, web applications tests and utilization of test automation and performance tools.

IT Teacher

Government of Santa Catarina

February 2016 – December 2016 and August 2011 – June 2012

Responsible for teaching computing classes for young students in Windows and Linux environment at state schools. Assigned to help teachers and employees in the utilization in electronics equipment and computers.

Help Desk

Criciúma City Hall

January 2010 - August 2011

Responsible for creation and maintenance of networks and subnetworks, besides of assembly, setting and maintenance of computers, servers, and printers. Assigned to deal with clients and users through of personal services and telephonic, besides of knowledges in Windows and Linux environment installation and maintenance software.

Education

Degree in Computer Education

Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina – UDESC August 2017 - August 2021

Graduate Degree Technologies for Web Applications

Universidade Norte do Paraná – UNOPAR

August 2014 - August 2015

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense – UNESC February 2010 - July 2014

Languages

Portuguese: Native, maternal language

English: Read, write, understand, and speak: C1 level Spanish: Read, write, understand, and speak: B2 level



Skills

Test Automation	
Manual Testing	
Test Strategy	
Test Management	
Java	
JavaScript	
Software Development	
Leadership	

REST API testing	REST Assured	Cucumber	BDD	Cypress
Elastic	Kafka	Couchbase	Supertest	Mobile testing
Spring Appium	Gherkin	BrowserStack	Git	BitBucket
Jira	Zephyr	Jenkins	Xcode	JMeter
Postman	Lombok	Docker	Maven	AWS
MySQL	Postgres	H2	Charles	Android Studio
Xcode	Visual Studio Code	IntelliJ	Junit	RabbitMQ
Team Work	Customers	Support	Selenium	Scrum
Kanban	jQuery	CSS	HTML	Bootstrap